CAROLINE : " l lost no time , of course ,
" in telling my mother all that I knew
" and we saw ourselves at once in a difficult and dangerous position .
" Something must speedily be resolved upon , and it occurred to us
" at last to go forth together and seek help in the neighboring hamlet .
" No sooner said than done . Bare-headed as we were ,
" we ran out at once in the gathering evening and the frosty fog .
" The hamlet lay not many hundred yards away
" though out of view , on the other side of the next cove
" and what greatly encouraged me
" it was in an opposite direction
" from that whence the blind man had made his appearance .
" And I shall never forget how much I was cheered
" to see the yellow shine in doors and windows ,
" but that , as it proved
" was the best of the help we were likely to get in that quarter .
" For you would have thought
" men would have been ashamed of themselves ,
" no soul would consent to return with us to the ... "
Audrey ? Sorry .
Mr. Talcott 's gone .
Okay .
Front desk , in case anyone shows .
I think you 'll be waiting a while , hon .
No . Didn 't we call ? He said he had family .
Yeah . But they don 't wanna have anything to do with him .
You can dump it out back .
( SIGHS )
( BAND PLAYING )
Okay , take a look .
I interview tomorrow .
What about yourjob ?
I had enough of that place .
Why , what happened ? Here 's your beer .
Thanks . Sure .
I lost a patient today . Mr. Talcott .
I 'm sorry . You should have seen it .
The second he died , it was like
they couldn 't wait to get him out of there .
It 's just a business to them .
It is a business , but at least he had you .
No. lt 's supposed to be a business about caring .
They couldn 't care less .
Wait . This is Terrebonne Parish . It 's the freaking swamps .
I get the hours I need to start nursing school , and I get paid .
And I get to help somebody , my way .
They got gators in the swamps , and guys missing teeth .
Are we dancing here , or what ?
Cary , look .
This work you 're doing , are you sure it 's not changing you ?
I 'm 25 years old . What 's wrong with a little change ?
( BAND CONTINUES PLAYING )
( DEATH LETTER PLAYING )
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
Oh , my God .
( ROCKING CHAIR CREAKING )
Hello ?
( KNOCKING )
( GASPS )
Hello ?
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
LUKE : Now that right there is what love is all about .
Old-fashioned devotion , like what you read about .
You must be Caroline .
I 'm sorry , the door was open , so I just walked in .
Oh , no. lt 's a big house . I didn 't hear you .
LUKE : It 's okay .
( BOTH LAUGH )
So much for getting their affairs in order .
I 'm sorry. I 'm Luke Marshall . Estate lawyer .
We talked on the phone .
Oh , right .
The docs figure a month maybe . He 's pretty far gone .
CAROLINE : I understand .
His wife 's having kind of a rough time with it .
Most people do .
( GRUNTS )
LUKE : Violet , you have a visitor .
May I present Miss Caroline Ellis ?
She works down at the hospice in New Orleans .
Caroline , this is Violet Devereaux .
You have a lovely home .
I 'm sorry. lt 's just hard . The idea of a stranger living here ...
I understand , really .
She 's Old South , you know . She thinks women still curtsey .
So , he can 't talk at all ?
No . Stroke pretty much paralyzed him .
Which side was affected ? Both .
It happened about a month ago , up in the attic .
That 's where she found him .
Ben ?
You have a visitor . Meet Miss Caroline Ellis .
Hello , Ben . I 'm Caroline .
VIOLET : She 's not from around here .
She 's not gonna understand my house .
She 's from New Orleans .
She wasn 't raised in New Orleans . You hear how she talks ?
Who knows where she comes from ? Hoboken , New Jersey .
What , do you want a Southern accent ?
The last one left , Violet .
All right .
But she 's not gonna understand the house .
The last girl left , huh ?
LUKE : Wait . Let me talk to her , we can straighten things out .
I can 't help anybody who doesn 't want my help .
She does want help . She 's just scared .
Of what ? Politeness ?
No . He 's the love of her life and he 's dying .
They 've been together forever .
She 's losing her soul mate here .
I don 't know about you , but that 'd put some sandpaper up my ass .
Aren 't you a romantic ?
Look .
The last girl quit .
You 're the fifth interview since .
She shoots down everyone .
It 's not personal .
But you being here means he 's really dying .
He 's dying whether I 'm here or not .
What 'd she mean about the house ?
What ?
She said I wouldn 't understand the house . Why 'd she said that ?
All I know is her checks clear .
Look , forget it .
If it makes you feel any better , I 'm still looking for my dream job , too .
All right .
So if you talked to her , what would you say ?
I 'd say she could look all she wants
but I doubt she 'd find any better than you .
So she 'd do well to treat you like it .
JILL : Okay , here are my rules . No knitting .
No joining a bridge club .
And no playing bingo .
Okay , good . Good rules .
I 'm serious , they 'll try and suck you into their elderly ways .
It 's less than an hour away . I 'll be back all the time .
Yeah , well , you better .
Whenever you want to talk to someone who wasn 't around for World War ll .
Jeez , what is it with you and old people ?
Come here .
He 'd be proud of you . You know he would .
( BLUES MUSIC PLAYING )
( BIRD CAWING )
( PHONOGRAPH PLAYING )
Hello ?
I need to pay for some gas .
( BEE BUZZING )
Hello ?
( BABY CRYING )
( PHONOGRAPH SWITCHING OFF )
ls somebody back there ?
( GASPS )
I 'm sorry .
Excuse me. I just need to pay for some gas .
( BABY CRYING )
( WOMAN SPEAKING CREOLE )
( BABY CONTINUES CRYING )
Jesus .
( GASPS )
( SPEAKING CREOLE )
$ 17 for the gas .
Keep the change .
CAROLINE : Mrs. Devereaux ?
I 'm unpacked .
( COME ON in MY KITCHEN PLAYING ON PHONOGRAPH )
Hi , Ben . Remember me ? I 'm Caroline .
I 'll be taking care of you for a while .
There 's not a lot of light in here for you , is there ?
So you 're a fan of the blues , huh ? Well , so was ...
You have to let go .
Ben , you 're hurting me .
Ouch .
VIOLET : There you are .
Time for his remedies .
Scoot over , child .
VIOLET : 0 : 00 in the morning and 7 : 00 at night .
He takes his pills in powder form . I 'll show you how .
Be sure he drinks it all down .
CAROLINE : What 's he taking ? Oh , Coumadin and such .
He gets the tremors sometimes . Don 't let that frighten you .
And a kiss to make it taste better .
You 're scrawnier than I 'd hoped . Prettier , though .
I bet you 're all marked up , aren 't you ?
Marked up ? Written on .
I know you young people are always
jabbing yourselves with ink and needles .
You 're written on , aren 't you ?
Not where you can see .
Well .
He 's to be bathed daily , his linens changed .
Don 't bother with the housework. I 'm the only one that knows how .
How long have you two lived here ?
Let 's see .
We came over from Savannah in ' 62 .
We bought this house from a brother and a sister .
They 'd inherited it a long time ago , from their parents .
Lived here since they were children .
There they are . Martin and Grace .
Charming people .
But they fell on hard times , had to sell .
You keep their picture ?
Yes. I like to pay my respects to the memories of this house .
VIOLET : All right . Come along now .
This is the dining room .
We only use about half of the rooms .
The others are for Ben 's antique business .
What he couldn 't sell , we stored here .
Except for the attic .
That has crystal and china .
And I keep a very close account on that , just so as you know .
There are more than 30 rooms in all .
In the old days , they made a separate key for each room .
For the owner , they made a skeleton key .
This will open every door .
This one is yours .
I have mine .
Now , the pantry 's right out here .
You know , we may have to ask you to go into town now and then .
Was there a mirror here once ?
I noticed in the bathrooms also there are no mirrors .
Child , when you get as worn-out and wrinkled as we are ,
you don 't need any reminding .
If you want a small one for your own purposes
that 's fine with me .
What 'd you do with them ? Put them away .
The boy tells me you don 't smoke .
I do smoke. I smoke a lot and I enjoy it very much .
I trust that won 't be an issue .
It won 't be .
Good . Then for the most part just realize that
I 'll live here as if you 're not in residence .
After all , we 're not kin . Are your parents still alive ?
My mom left when I was little .
My dad raised me and he died last year .
Oh , my . So you cared for him as well ?
I would have .
I just thought I had more time .
You think too much about the time you have left ,
you don 't spend it living .
Be good to my husband . Be good to his house .
Remedies at 0 : 00 .
CAROLINE : One , two , three .
( GRUNTS )
You don 't see gardens like this back in New Jersey , I expect .
Actually , it 's the Garden State .
( CHUCKLING ) I doubt that very much .
Nothing more glorious than a garden .
Gone every winter , back every spring .
You religious at all ?
I try to keep an open mind .
That 's good . That 's very good .
Where are my trilliums ?
Oh , fiddlesticks . Do me a blessing , child .
Will you run up to the attic for me ?
I have some seed packets in a box right next to the stairs .
( DOOR CREAKING )
( THUDDING )
( RATTLING )
( GASPS )
What took you ?
( SIGHS )
I 'm sorry .
I thought the key opens everything .
The key ? What key ?
The key you gave me for the house .
There 's a door in the attic it doesn 't work for .
Oh , no , the attic , it 's never opened that .
I got my Dixie-Johns . Why not ?
What 's in there ? I have no idea .
It 's been shut ever since we moved in .
I have to get these in the ground , because there 's rain coming .
Mrs. Devereaux ,
Ben was in the attic , wasn 't he , when he had his stroke ?
What was he doing in there ?
You 'll have to ask him , child .
Be a dear and go see to him , won 't you ?
I wonder if he wouldn 't like some iced tea .
( WATER RUNNING )
( DOOR CREAKING )
( FOOTSTEPS )
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( WOOD CREAKING )
( MOANING )
( THUDDING )
( SIGHS )
( METALLIC RATTLING )
( RATTLING )
( RATTLING CONTINUES )
His door was locked .
Ben !
( GASPING )
Stop right there , Ben ! Don 't move !
Stop !
Ben !
Mrs. Devereaux !
( GRUNTING )
Ben !
( GRUNTING ) Ben , what are you doing ? It 's me !
( CONTINUES GRUNTING )
Mother of mercy , what 're you doing ?
He got out of the window . I thought you said he was bedridden .
He 's having spasms .
Didn 't you give him his remedies ? Yes .
Did you make sure he drank them all down ? I thought so .
Ben , what 'd they make you do ? His door was locked .
Just go get the wheelchair . We 've gotta get him out of this .
What about a doctor ?
In the morning , just get that wheelchair now .
VIOLET : Caroline !
What in damnation took you so long ?
I came as fast as I could .
We 're just gonna have to double his remedies . That 's all I can think of .
Caroline , help me here . Help me get him .
Come on . That 's it .
( BIRD CAWING )
Where did you think you were going ?
LUKE : You 're here two days and he already tried to kill himself .
Must have some kind of bedside manner , huh ?
Among my many charms .
So , what exactly happened ? I came to update her will ,
she 's up with the doc , says he fell ?
He did fall .
Like what , from his wheelchair ?
( SIGHS )
You cannot be serious . From up there ? He fell from up there ?
How ? He can 't even walk .
Don 't tell me you 're quitting . I have to start over again .
Will you shut the door ? I want to show you something .
You know what my mama used to say ?
If a lady invites you into her room , she probably isn 't much of a lady .
Homespun Southern wisdom grows on trees around here , doesn 't it ?
I found this in Ben 's room
last night .
Found what ? His laundry ?
No , it had a ...
There was ... Had a what ?
There was a ... It had a ...
Forget it .
I thought it ...
I don 't know what I thought .
I admire you .
You know , what you do .
Hell , I wouldn 't be able to take care of my own parents .
You 'd regret it .
I quit college to help out with some friends ' bands .
Out all night , always on the road .
My father thought I was throwing my life away .
So we didn 't talk , didn 't visit .
Stubborn and proud , and that 's how we left it .
You mean ...
Yeah .
He was gone before I even knew he was sick .
I guess he wanted to spare me from all this .
is that so wrong ?
No one should have to die alone .
So tell me what you were gonna tell me .
About Ben .
Do you ever feel like
he 's asking you for help ?
Asking me ? With a look or
a touch .
VIOLET : Mr. Marshall ?
Where in damnation is that boy ? Caroline ,
have you seen Mr ...
Well ,
I see the children are getting acquainted .
Now , Violet ,
you know you 're the only woman in my life .
I know no such things , and remove your perspirations .
The doctor has departed , so I 'm ready
to discuss estate matters , if you have finished
soliciting your new business .
All right .
Whenever you get the time .
VIOLET : Caroline ?
I 'm making some sweet tea .
Are you interested ?
Caroline ?
" Sacrifice . "
Are you in the house ?
( DOOR CREAKING )
( GASPING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Caroline ?
You 're forgetful , child .
( GASPS )
PAPA JUSTIFY : It is time , Lord .
From the dry dust ,
out of these chains
from the devil 's house .
It is time , Lord ,
to take me
from the dry dust , break me from these chains .
Bring me from the devil 's house .
Take me out of darkness .
Walk me out of blindness .
Lift me out of sadness .
Save me from my damned-ness .
Please , Lord .
It is time , Lord .
Take me from the dry dust . Break me
out of these chains . Bring me from the devil 's house .
Take me out of ...
Just a local band .
How about you buy me a drink ?
( MUSIC PLAYING )
Whatever it is , it 's not your average attic .
She says it 's been locked up ever since they first moved in .
You found yourself a hoodoo room .
A what ? Hoodoo . You know what hoodoo is ?
It 's like voodoo , right ?
JILL : Wrong . Voodoo 's a religion .
Slaves brought it to Haiti from Africa .
You worship God , heaven and hell .
How 's hoodoo different ? It 's magic .
American folk magic . God doesn 't have much to do with it .
Magic ? Yeah .
It 's part African , part European , part Native American .
And New Orleans is its home . It started here .
My Aunt Nola 's into it . She shops at a place in Algiers .
Look , you said the house had a history , right ?
Hoodoo is pretty harmless . Harmless how ?
It 's psychological , like a lot of that stuff .
It can 't hurt you if you don 't believe .
So this place your aunt shops at ...
Ever seen it ?
It 's either this street or the next one
or the next one .
There .
There ? That 's a Laundromat .
Look , that 's all I know . That 's where she goes .
So you coming in or what ?
I 'm not .
I thought you don 't believe in this stuff .
I don 't .
But I 'm not just going to mess around with it .
So , you wanna go in , go ahead .
You 're scared .
Jill the Thrill is scared . Kiss my ass .
You 're never gonna live this down . We come all the way out here ...
I 'm not scared .
( SIGHS )
( CREAKING )
VIOLET : Good night , Caroline .
Good night .
( BANGING ON DOOR )
I told you about the mirrors .
I don 't understand .
This is not your house .
I found them . I needed a mirror for my bathroom ...
I told you , and you heard me . No mirrors .
No mirrors !
I 've seen the room .
What room ? The room you say you 've never seen .
It 's not locked anymore .
No , child , you don 't know what you 've seen .
You 're gonna tell me right now .
Or I 'm leaving .
You 're not from the South .
You won 't understand .
That room up there , you just don 't go in and
throw things out of a room like that .
You leave them just where you found them .
The house is theirs just as much as ours .
The house is whose ? Whose things are in that room ?
All right .
About 00 years ago
there was a banker here , his name was Thorpe .
He made his fortune cheating the poor .
He was a mean man . He was a cruel man .
It was him , and his family , and couple of servants
name of Mama Cecile and Papa Justify .
Sit down .
The way I heard it , old man Thorpe , he didn 't know
that Papa Justify was a " two-headed doctor . "
He was a conjure man . So was Cecile .
They believed in ... Hoodoo .
Yeah .
That was their room .
They were famous all through the bayous .
They healed the sick and they hurt the mean .
" Hit a straight lick with a crooked stick , " as the coloreds say .
But old Thorpe , he just saw them as help .
And he worked them to the bone .
He abused them .
Until one night , as the story goes
there was a party .
It was the bank 's anniversary , all the big mucketymucks were here .
Politicians , sugar barons , riverboat tycoons .
There was a lot of drinking and dancing
and a couple of trysts , I 'm sure .
And then , finally , when it was time to say farewell
some of the guests wanted to wish goodbye to the children .
But nobody could find them . They hadn 't seen them in hours .
So , being all full of brandy , they made it a game .
" Let 's Find the Children . "
Room after room after room .
Finally , someone heard music ...
Martin ? Grace ?
... and voices and shouting
up in the attic .
PAPA JUSTIFY : From the devil 's house .
It is time , Lord .
VIOLET : The servants were up there with the children .
They were trying to teach them how to conjure hoodoo .
MAN : And take his head .
Thorpe went about insane , and so did the rest of the guests .
I mean , how long had this blasphemy been going on ?
The children said it was their fault , that they 'd wanted to learn .
But they weren 't having any of that .
( SCREAMING )
( WOMAN WAILING )
( ALL CLAMORING )
All that power and rage and insanity .
The party was over .
It was a terrible thing .
Terrible .
Rumors got out , but no arrests , no trial .
Money had its way .
What happened to the family ?
The bank went under .
Thorpe shot his wife to death , and then turned the gun on himself .
People in the bayou say it was Justify and Cecile 's revenge .
The children stayed here till ' 62 .
But they never , ever , told us why that room was locked .
Or why there were no mirrors in the whole house .
Now we know .
You know what ?
You see them in the mirrors .
Who ?
The servants .
I 've gone and read some hoodoo books , and they say
putting brick dust down will keep harm away .
So I made a big circle of it around the whole house .
You can 't expect me to believe you see ghosts in your mirrors .
The ghosts are here now .
But whatever they did to him
I am not going to let them do it to me .
Now you 'll leave
like all the rest of them .
( BIRD CALLING )
That 's some superstitious wife you got there , Ben .
She thinks you have ghosts in the attic .
Spooky , huh ?
Ouch .
Hold on . I 'll be right back .
She says you see them in the mirrors .
Ghosts in the mirrors .
( GRUNTING )
I 'm sorry , Ben .
( GASPING )
Ben , stop it . Shh .
Relax. I 'm so ...
I 'm so sorry .
( PANTING )
CAROLINE : I 'm so sorry .
You see them , too .
I 'm going to town .
Shopping .
VIOLET : What for , Caroline ?
Caroline , what for ?
We 'll just have to see .
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
MAMA CYNTHIA : He won 't beat you again .
WOMAN : Mama Cynthia , he beat me last night .
You use the potion that I 'm gonna fix for you
and it won 't happen again . I will promise you that .
I 'm scared . Don 't be afraid .
Are you sure that I can do it ?
I know it will . It will work .
Just do as I say . Don 't be afraid .
It will work , and it won 't happen again , ever .
Don 't worry about it . He won 't hit you again .
Just use this potion I mixed up .
I have a lot of things in here .
And you use it as I told you .
Okay , I trust you , Mama . You 'll do fine .
That brick dust at the door , how does it work ?
You lay a line down .
Nobody that means you harm can cross it .
It 's how you tell who your enemies are .
It 's like hypnotism , right ?
Suggestion ?
And when this stuff works , it 's because someone believes it works ?
And if you thought , you know ,
magic made you sick
you might believe in a magic cure , right ?
Even though it 's all in your head .
Somebody been working roots on you .
Say I knew someone who believed he 'd been ...
Crossed . Crossed .
Would he believe he could be uncrossed ?
What 's the nature of his condition ?
He can 't speak . Barely moves . He had a stroke
but he seems to think someone else made him that way .
And you want to know what happened to him ?
Yes .
( HUMMING )
JILL : You went in there . You actually went in .
Are you out of your mind ?
Come on . Haven 't you ever heard of psychosomatic treatment ?
Yeah . But this is not that .
How much of a patient 's recovery depends on his believing he can ?
What recovery ? This is hospice .
You 're just supposed to help this guy die .
He believes in this stuff .
So what ? Who is he to you ?
Forget it .
No , you forget it . He 's not your dad .
Not this one , the last one , or the one before .
Why are the two of you so attached ?
I 'm sorry , Cary .
Just so you know , if I 'm not attached to him
I 'm abandoning him .
Attached is better .
I know . Cary , I 'm sorry . Okay ?
But would you look at yourself ?
You want to be a nurse and you just walked out of a witch doctor 's .
It 's not for me .
( THUNDER CLAPPING )
WOMAN ON TV : Forecasters are calling for up to a foot of rain
in the coastal areas
as this storm makes its way across the delta , starting overnight .
Radar already shows increasing precipitation
across the coastal areas and moving rather quickly to the north .
The main forecast concerns centers around potential ...
( BLUES MUSIC PLAYING )
Hi , Ben .
I 'm gonna show you something .
It 's going to be our secret . You and me .
Violet says you didn 't have a stroke
in the attic . She said some ghosts
made you this way with a spell .
is that what you think ?
Because I know a spell , too , Ben .
One that makes you better .
All you have to do is believe it .
Backwards .
( CLEARS THROAT )
Cleanse this man .
Cleanse this room .
Cleanse this house .
His words have gotten lost , lost and wandering in his mind .
Let the water run down
and wash away this condition .
His tongue has gotten tied , tied and tangled in his throat .
Let the water run down
and wash away this affliction .
Send his voice to go free .
Let the water run down
and wash away ...
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( GURGLES )
Caroline .
( GASPING )
( STAMMERING ) Caroline .
It 's all in your head .
Help . Help .
Ben , talk to me . Keep talking .
Help me .
Help you ? Help you how , Ben ?
Get me out of here .
( DOORKNOB RATTLING )
VIOLET : Caroline ?
Caroline ?
( SCREAMING ) Get me out of here !
CAROLINE : Shit !
( BANGING ON DOOR ) Caroline !
Just a second .
VIOLET : Caroline , open this door !
What are you doing to him ?
Ben , why ? Get out of here , why ?
VIOLET : Caroline ! One second !
VIOLET : Caroline , open this door !
I 'll help you , I promise . Just talk to me .
What happened to you in that attic ? Tell me who you 're afraid of .
( DOOR OPENING )
What have you done ?
What is this ?
He was ...
He was struggling in his sleep ...
VIOLET : Get away from him .
Get away from him . He was struggling .
VIOLET : It 's all right .
I brought water .
You were talking to him ?
I was just telling him a story to settle him down .
VIOLET : About what ? Just a story .
No ghosts .
That 'll be all tonight , Caroline . Thank you .
I 'll come back to check on him ...
No , that won 't be necessary . That 's all for tonight . Good night .
( CLICKING )
( CAROLINE GASPING )
PAPA JUSTIFY : It is time , Lord .
( ECHOING )
( GROANS )
It is time , Lord .
Grace .
WOMAN : Caroline ?
Caroline .
( GASPING )
( GASPS )
Mrs. Devereaux ?
( THUNDER CLAPPING )
( SQUAWKING )
Her and her ghost shit .
CAROLINE : That attic is filled with this stuff .
Recipes . Spells . Books of them . Records of them .
I understand your cause of concern
but my family is superstitious , too . We 're called Baptists .
This is different . It 's charming .
Local color .
You said yourself you were worried about him .
Well , now I 'm worried about you . You know ?
Are you a nurse or a detective ?
When did you first meet the Devereauxs ?
Just before he had his stroke .
They were looking for a lawyer to update their wills .
Did you ever think that maybe she knew something
was gonna happen to him ?
How ? Like tarot cards in the attic ? A s · ance in her sleep ?
I want to know why the last girl quit .
Hallie . Some folks to see you .
HALLIE : You a superstitious person , Caroline ?
CAROLINE : Not per se .
HALLIE : I told my mama where l was working .
She said that house has been nothing but blood and tears .
That the last owners were some rich brother and sister .
Crazy people , supposedly .
They died of strokes right after they sold the place .
Maybe they found something they shouldn 't .
Maybe now Ben did , too .
It may be their mess in that room
but ain 't no ghosts put a spell on that old man .
She did .
Do you believe that ? Don 't you ?
But I heard it can 't hurt you .
I mean , it can 't hurt you if you don 't believe .
Then I suggest you leave that house before you do .
( BLUES MUSIC PLAYING )
LUKE : For God 's sake , this is insane . The man had a stroke .
CAROLINE : So why isn 't that what he thinks ?
And you 're gonna take him away from her ? From his own wife ?
How can you believe ... I don 't believe. I don 't .
The point is , he does .
Stop the car . What ?
Stop the car . Why ?
I 've been here before . I 'll show you . It 's not just them .
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
See the line across the doorway ? It 's brick dust .
Hoodoo . Keeps your enemies from coming across .
See the bones hanging ?
This stuff 's got a hold on people out here .
Yeah , but it 's not real .
It doesn 't matter if it 's not real . It 's real to them .
( MUSIC PLAYING )
What 's wrong ?
CAROLINE : This music. I know this music .
You sure this is a good idea ?
Hello ?
Mama raised a gentleman .
CAROLINE : Hello ?
( ROCKING CHAIR CREAKING )
Excuse me . Ma 'am ?
CAROLINE : We heard the music , your record . I was wondering ...
There 's no record for anyone here .
How about records by a man named Justify ?
How do you know that name ?
Who sent you ?
Who else is in here ?
Someone else in here ? It 's just me , ma 'am .
Stop now . Don 't you go touching ...
Do you know a record called the Conjure of Sacrifice ?
Because I have it , if you do .
You had that , you wouldn 't say so .
You do know it .
The strongest conjuration of all . They say Justify discovered it
but he got killed before he learned to work it .
Him and his poor wife both . It 's never been found .
What does it do ?
It keeps you from dying .
Not forever , but for a while .
How ?
You have to sacrifice somebody
and take the years that they have left .
( THUNDER CLAPPING )
Hurry up ! He 's all alone with her !
Hang on , Caroline ! Wait ! Shit !
Now you got me spooked .
If I get proof that she 's out to hurt him , will you stick by me ...
By " hurt him , " you mean kill him . Will you or won 't you ?
Just listen to yourself .
Fine . Goodbye .
What are you gonna do here , you gonna kidnap him ?
You know something 's wrong between them . You know it .
Let me make some calls . See about grounds for
a restraining order , protective custody .
You 're not gonna get a search warrant till tomorrow anyhow .
Then that 'll give me tonight .
I 'm all he 's got , Luke . Me .
Get the proof . Okay ?
CAROLINE : Mrs. Devereaux , I 'm back .
No . Where 's the record ?
It was right here .
Mrs. Devereaux , could you come here for a second ?
Caroline , I was beginning to worry about you ,
you were gone such a long while .
Yeah , it 's really raining out there .
It 's supposed to pour all night .
Keeps up like this , that swamp 's going to rise
and ruin my flowerbeds .
Did you want to see me ?
Yeah , I was wondering if you could take a look at this ?
There 's a leak up here .
They 're all over the house . They 're just rainwater .
Yes , but if you look up close ...
Come on in . I could show it to you better .
Well , it ...
Actually , I have supper on the stove .
I shouldn 't leave it .
It 'll just take a second . I can see perfectly from here .
You want this for the sill ?
All right .
Could you come into the room please , just for a second ?
So I can show you what I 'm seeing .
You 're a funny one , Caroline .
I 'll make us some tea .
VIOLET : And , Caroline ?
After you 've given Mr. Devereaux his remedies
would you be so kind as to join an old lady for supper ?
Well , I ... Wonderful !
We should have done it days ago .
I 've made something real nice .
( lKO lKO PLAYING )
We 're leaving tonight .
VIOLET : Caroline !
Supper .
( THUNDER CLAPPING )
How 's your gumbo ?
I haven 't started .
Would you like sugar for your tea ? I put it out for you .
No , I don 't think I 'll have any sugar tonight .
But I thought you liked it .
You always have sugar in your tea .
You think I 'm senile , don 't you ?
Ghosts in the attic . Spells on my husband .
I just don 't understand .
These ghosts , why would they put a spell on him and not me ?
I 've been in that room , too .
Maybe because you don 't believe in them .
Maybe all houses have spirits
but we just don 't see them until we believe we can .
I 'm really not that hungry .
Don 't move . I 'll fetch the candles .
Eat your gumbo . Oh , fiddlesticks .
Dinner by candlelight .
There .
So , was that the storm or the ghosts ?
Well , say what you will about spirits .
I 've always wondered if there wasn 't something
we could learn from them .
Like a spell ?
I have great respect for your husband .
And whatever he thinks happened to him , he 's fighting it .
What did happen to him , Violet ?
You haven 't touched your gumbo .
What have you done to him ?
I made that special for you , and you haven 't even touched it .
What have you done ?
He is my husband , and I am his wife ,
and I will do to him whatever I wish to do !
He 's not safe in this house .
What ?
What is this ?
You 've done something .
He 's not safe in this house . Not with you .
This is my house . I 'm taking him , Violet .
No !
( GASPING )
Too late . Not again .
You little whore . He 's mine .
Keep him in this house .
Keep him in this ...
He 's mine !
CAROLINE : " Protection . "
Where 's the record ?
Oh , God .
Got it .
You bitch .
Time to go .
( BEN GRUNTS )
CAROLINE : Come on , Ben .
I 'm going to get you out of here . Just hold on .
( GROANS )
Damn it !
Keep him in this house .
Hold on .
( CAROLINE SCREAMS )
Caroline ?
CAROLINE : Oh , shit !
Caroline .
( GRUNTING )
Come on , Ben !
We 've got to hide you , Ben .
( GROANS )
( BEN GRUNTING )
( GASPING )
I 'm gonna get help . I won 't leave you .
I won 't leave you .
Okay ?
Caroline ?
( GUN FIRING )
You think you can take him out of this house ?
You think you 're stronger than me ?
You 've no idea how strong I am , Caroline .
( GASPS )
VIOLET : Caroline !
You 're just making it harder on yourself !
Where are you ?
VIOLET : You can 't get away , Caroline .
You understand me ?
You 'll never get out of here , child .
Caroline ?
Caroline .
VIOLET : Stop right there !
( GUN FIRING )
( MUSIC PLAYING )
( PEOPLE CHATTERING )
Thank you .
( DOORBELL BUZZING )
Luke !
Jesus Christ .
She tried to kill me .
She had a gun .
She knows I know . Ben 's in trouble .
He 's still at the house . Call the police , Luke . I left him .
We got to get back out there .
The hell we do .
I left him there .
You didn 't leave anyone . Okay ? Slow down .
Tell me what happened . She tried to kill you ?
( CELL PHONE RINGING )
Sorry .
Mrs. Devereaux .
To what do I owe the ...
Heard from Caroline ? Why would she have ...
What 's going on ?
Okay . What happened tonight ?
Hang on a second .
We need to record this .
( lKO lKO PLAYING )
Hurting him ? Hurting him how ?
What do you mean ? What are you talking about ?
I am listening to you .
( GASPING )
Good night , child .
( BLUES MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO )
( GASPS )
LUKE : A hell of a thing , isn 't it ?
See , everywhere you look ,
it 's a whole new world all around you .
It 's like being born .
Or dying . Of course , I wouldn 't know .
( SOBBING )
( MUFFLED SHOUTS )
Hush , darling . I know it 's hard .
We 're home !
He 's missing . She 's hidden him somewhere .
Where is he , Caroline ?
It 's not him , it 's me .
You want to sacrifice me .
Where is he , Caroline ?
Why are you helping her ?
is everything ready ? VIOLET : No .
I can 't start anything till I know where he is .
What 's our tale if he gets away ?
Caroline ,
you will tell me exactly where my husband is .
There 's nothing anybody can do for him , so there 's no need to try .
Where is he ?
Where is he , Caroline ?
He 's in the garden shed .
Don 't scratch her up any more than she already is .
She 's teaching you .
You help her kill me , and she 'll teach you how .
Ben knew , too , didn 't he ?
That 's enough , Caroline .
You want to shoot me , shoot me .
Stop right there , Caroline !
I want my father 's picture .
I want it with me .
Please .
Jesus . All right .
You want your picture , I 'll get your goddamn picture .
( GRUNTS )
( GUN CLICKING )
Fuck !
Violet , she 's going outside !
Violet !
She 's here !
VIOLET : Quick ! Go get her ! Help me !
Come on .
She 's fixed the door !
Violet , I can 't get up the stairs !
( GASPS )
You try to use my tricks on me ?
( SCREAMING )
On me , huh ?
( SCREAMS )
( GROANING )
( GROANS )
No !
( PHONE ENGAGED TONE )
( DIAL TONE )
( PHONE RINGING )
WOMAN : 911 emergency .
( STAMMERING ) My name is Caroline Ellis .
I 'm at 1750 ,
Bayou Chapelet in Terrebonne Parish .
I need police and paramedics .
There are people hurt here . We 're trapped .
Please hurry .
( PHONE RINGING )
JILL : What time is it ? Jill .
Jill . Cary ?
Jill , I 'm in trouble .
Caroline ?
CAROLINE : It 's real .
It 's all real . You 're where ? What ?
I 'm in the Devereaux house .
Caroline .
What 's real ? What ...
( PHONE GOES DEAD )
Jill ?
( SOBBING )
( GASPS )
( BANGING ON DOOR )
VIOLET : Caroline !
You can 't get away , Caroline .
Oh , God , no .
VIOLET : Caroline .
CAROLINE : " Chalk , sulfur , blood , hair . "
Sulfur .
Candle .
Chalk .
Hurry !
Circle .
Eyes .
Four eyes . North , south .
Hurry ! Oh , God , please .
What 's next ?
Hair .
My child
I believe you broke my legs .
You can 't touch me .
You can 't get near me . See this ? This is your spell of protection .
is that what that is now ?
And who exactly gave you that spell ?
All that circle protects is you ,
from leaving it .
( CHUCKLES )
You stay back !
I 'll kill you ! You stay away !
We 've been waiting for you , Caroline .
Waiting for you to believe .
It doesn 't work if you don 't believe .
PAPA JUSTIFY : It is time , Lord .
From the dry dust out of these chains .
CAROLINE : I don 't believe .
I don 't .
I think you do .
The weakness is the flesh . The flesh , the flesh .
I don 't believe .
I don 't believe in it .
( VIOLET LAUGHING )
The flesh . The coil .
I don 't believe .
The frail . The weak .
CAROLINE : I don 't believe .
( RUMBLING )
I don 't ...
No .
Oh , my God .
( SCREAMING )
I don 't believe !
( SCREAMING ) I don 't believe !
( GLASS CRUNCHING )
Thank you , child .
Cecile ?
You all right ?
I 'm fine now , Justify .
A fair bit harder than the lawyer , wasn 't she ?
It 's harder every time .
They just don 't believe like they used to .
Got to get them riled up .
Mmm .
I told you I wanted a black one this time .
You know the black ones never stay .
Beggars can 't be choosers .
I think it fits you beautifully .
It 's better than Violet , or Grace , even .
We 'll get used to it . We always do .
( VIOLET GROANS )
The thing folks don 't understand about sacrifice ...
( GASPING )
Get me out of here .
... sometimes it 's more of a trade .
No !
There , there , Caroline .
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
CAROLINE : We thought it was just a fall
but now she can 't move or even speak .
Like a stroke or something .
JILL : Cary ?
Dearie me .
You called me .
I called you ?
( GASPING )
For help . Don 't you remember ?
Cary 's not herself right now . I 'm Luke Marshall .
Devereauxs ' lawyer . Hi . Jill Dupay , her roommate .
Jill , yes , I did call you .
Fiddlesticks. I don 't know what possessed me .
It 's all right. I 'm here .
They need real care now .
They can 't stay here .
This is all my fault .
No , Cary . No , it 's not .
It 's not .
( VIOLET GROANING )
Someone should ride to the hospital with them . Maybe ...
Jill , would you mind ? And we 'll meet you .
Of course . Whatever you need .
She meant so much to them , her being here .
I know it wasn 't for long , but
they really loved her .
Why do you say that ?
It 's in their wills .
They left her the house .
( DEATH LETTER PLAYING )
( SIREN WAILING )
( lF I CAN DREAM PLAYING )